# **Dario Di Pasquale**

Via Marco Polo 17, Bellizzi (SA), Italy darionovantadue@gmail.com +39 3899528723 (Cell) https://dariodip.github.io/ - https://www.linkedin.com/in/dario-di-pasquale



# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am a curious and passionate developer. I like my job and I like to learn and to solve problems. I spend much time learning new technologies in order to be up to date with current trends.

I want to improve myself as a person as well as a professional, becoming an expert in back-end architectures, highly-scalable systems, and distributed systems but also an expert in understanding customers' needs.

Someone could think that I like to deal with some technologies but actually, I like to solve problems using the right technology.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master's degree** in Networks and Software Technologies, February 2019 UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI DI SALERNO, Salerno, Italy

- Score: 110 cum laude (full marks with honours);
- Modules included: Distributed Systems, Data Compression, Advanced Computation Theory, Parallel, Concurrent and On-Cloud Programming;
- <u>Thesis</u>: Thesis on DSL development for highly-scalable cloud computing founded by ACT-OR and supervised by prof. Vittorio Scarano.

**Bachelor's degree** in Computer Science, October 2016 UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI DI SALERNO, Salerno, Italy

- Score: 110 cum laude (full marks with honours);
- Modules included: Programming Languages, Web Programming, Algorithms and Data Structures, Network Architectures, Networks Security;
- <u>Thesis</u>: Research thesis on Streaming Graph Partitioning for social graphs supervised by prof. Alberto Negro and prof. Gennaro Cordasco.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Like A Coffee, Italy

**Smart Contract Developer**, May 2018 – Present

Back-end developer and Smart Contract developer for a project concerning an authentication system, based on the Ethereum blockchain, aiming to address both privacy and scalability concerns:

- Responsible for the designing and the development of a proof-of-concept blockchain solution for the BlockID Authentication Service using zk-SNARKs, Express (Node.js), Solidity and Truffle;
- Responsible for the analysis of the customers' requirements;

King Web Design, Battipaglia (SA), Italy

Developer, May 2017 – October 2017

Designing and developing a dynamic server for data aggregation able to receive data in different formats from heterogeneous devices and to expose them through RESTful APIs;

Responsible for the designing and the development of the system using Flask (Python),
PHP, Docker, Redis, MongoDB.

NextEconomia, Rome, Italy

*Mobile developer*, April 2017 – October 2017

Designing and developing the cross-platform mobile application VotoColPortafoglio;

Responsible for designing and developing the application using React Native.

Smartour, Salerno, Italy

**Backend Developer**, February 2016 – July 2016

Backend developer for two applications: Smartour App and Giffoni Social Experience 2016.

- Responsible for designing and developing RESTful APIs using Express (Node.js), MongoDB, Redis;
- Responsible for designing and developing a CMS platform for managing applications' contents.

### SKILLS

- Languages: Italian (mother tongue), English (professional working proficiency);
- *Programming Languages:* excellent knowledge of Java, JavaScript and Python; good knowledge of Go, C, and Solidity; basic knowledge of Elixir, R, TypeScript, Scala and PHP;
- *Technologies:* excellent knowledge of Node.js, Express.js, Flask, MySQL and git; good knowledge of AWS, React.js, Blockchain Technologies, Ethereum, MongoDB, SQLite, Redis, Django and Docker; basic knowledge of CSS, Angular 2, React Native and Xtext;
- Other: good knowledge of P2P, Distributed Systems and Concurrent, Parallel and On-Cloud programming; basic knowledge of cryptography.

#### **INTERESTS**

Reading, Watching movies, Traveling, Biking, Playing (and watching) tennis